So let's talk about life.
我们来聊聊实际生活的例子
有时我们在生活中会犯两种错误
There are two errors that
sometimes we make in life.
第一种是用苍蝇拍来杀死哥斯拉龙
One is trying to kill
Godzilla with a flyswatter.
That's a pretty bad error to make.
这是非常愚蠢的错误
它过度简化了我们要解决的问题
It's oversimplifying the problem
we're trying to solve.
The other one is to try to
kill a fly with a bazooka.
另一种是用火箭筒杀死苍蝇
这也非常不实际
That's also pretty bad.
It's overcomplicating the problem
we're trying to solve.
它过度复杂化了我们要解决的问题
在机器学习中 我们也非常容易犯这两种错误
In machine learning, these two types
of errors are very easy to make.
当我们过度简化问题时 我们称之为欠拟合
When we oversimplify the problem,
we call this underfitting.
过度复杂化时 称之为过拟合
And when we overcomplicate the problem,
we call it overfitting.
我们更详细地认识一下过拟合和欠拟合
So let's look at underfitting and
overfitting in a bit more detail.
先看这样一个分类问题
Let's look at this
classification problem.
We need to find a property that
separates the set on the left
我们需要找到一个属性 将左边的集合
与右边的集合分开
from the set on the right.
看起来解决方法很简单
It seems like the solution is easy.
右边的集合元素都是狗
The set on the right is made of dogs,
and
the set on the left is made
of things that are not dogs.
左边的集合元素都不是
如果我们过度简化它会怎样？
But what if we oversimplify this?
假如我们说右边的都是动物
What if we say the set on
the right is made of animals, and
而左边的都不是动物
the set on the left is made
of everything but animals?
Then our model is is a bit too simple.
那么我们的模型就太简单了
而且可以看出我们已在训练集中犯了一个错误
And we can see that it already makes
a mistake on the training set,
since it misclassified
this cat on the left side.
因为猫被错误地分类到了左边
这种过度简化成为欠拟合
This oversimplification
is called underfitting.
One characteristic of it is that it
doesn't do well on the training set.
它的一个特点是训练集的拟合不够好
我们称这种类型为偏差引起的误差
We call this type of error
an error due to bias.
The other mistake we can make
is to overcomplicate the model.
我们会犯的另一个错误是过度复杂化模型
If instead of describing the set on
the right as dogs, we describe it as
这次我们不将右边的集合描述为狗
dogs that are wagging their tail,
then this seems to do the job well in
而是摇着尾巴的狗 这看起来在训练集中
的拟合效果会很好 但直觉告诉我们这样做不对
training set, but somehow our intuition
is telling us that this is not right.
在出现一个新实例时你就明白了
This can be confirmed when
you bring out a new instance.
For example, this dog over here.
例如这里这只狗
Our logic tells us this dog should
belong to the set on the right.
逻辑告诉我们这只狗应该属于右边的集合
但由于这只狗没有摇尾巴
But since the dog is
not wagging its tail,
此模型会错误地将它分类到左边的集合
then this model mistakenly classifies
it in the set on the left.
此错误称为过拟合 也就是说此模型太过具体
This error is called overfitting,
this means the model is too specific.
它的一个特点是它在训练集中表现良好
One characteristic of it is that it
does well in the training set but
但它趋向于记住而不是学习数据的特点
it tends to memorize it instead of
learning the characteristics of it, so
it will not do well on the testing set.
因此在测试集上的表现不好
We call this type of error
an error due to variance.
我们称这种错误为方差引起的误差
从技术层面来说
Let's get more technical.
在回归示例中 可以看到下面这样的欠拟合
In our regression example,
we can see underfitting as follows.
看看左边的点
Let's look at the points on the left.
看起来这些点的正确模型
It seems like the correct model for
this point is a quadratic
equation like this one.
是像这样的二次方程
We could try to model it as a line,
but this won't work too well,
我们可以尝试将它拟合成一条直线 但效果不太好
因为它太简单了
since it's too simple.
此模型在训练集上的效果不好
The model won't do well
in our training set.
这是欠拟合的示例
This is an example of underfitting.
Now, what if instead we try to
fit a polynomial of large degree
那么 如果我们尝试拟合一个大角度的多项式呢
就像这一个？
like this one?
这个多项式在训练集上的表现很好 完美拟合了点
This polynomial does great in
the training set, fits it perfectly, but
somehow it seems like
it's not the best answer.
但它似乎并非最佳答案
It memorizes the training set and
it fails to find good properties of
它记住了训练集 但未能找到训练集的
良好属性 以很好地泛化到测试集
the training set that will
generalize well to the testing set.
So even though it performs
well in the training set,
所以即使它在训练集上的表现很好
it will perform poorly
on the testing set.
但在测试集上的效果会很差
This is an example of overfitting.
这是过拟合的例子
我们也会在分类模型中看到欠拟合
We can see underfitting in
a classification model as well.
The red and
在这里 红色点
blue points seems to be nicely separated
by a quadratic curve like this one.
和蓝色点似乎很好地被这条二次曲线分隔开了
如果我们用直线的话 此模型不能正确地拟合点
When we try to use a line, the model
doesn't fit the points properly, and
it underfits.
会出现欠拟合
如果我们尝试拟合到非常复杂的曲线
And when we try to fit in a curve
that is very complicated,
we end up with a model
that is too complex.
最终会得到一个太过复杂的模型
它在测试集上的效果会很差
And this may not do well
in the testing set.
会出现过拟合
Thus it overfits.
So here's a small summary.
那么我们简单总结一下
一方面 我们获得高偏差误差或欠拟合
On one side, we get the errors due
to high bias, or underfitting.
This is where we
oversimplify the problem and
这里我们过度简化了问题
our model is too simple to capture
the complexity of our data.
我们的模型太简单 无法捕捉到数据的复杂性
On the other side, we get the errors
due to high variance or overfitting.
另一方面 我们获得高方差误差或过拟合
This is when we overcomplicate the
problem and our model is too complex and
我们在这里过度复杂化了问题 我们的模型太复杂
ends up memorizing our data
instead of learning it.
以至于记住了数据 而非学习了它
Then in the middle,
we've got the good model.
而中间的是最佳模型
When it comes to the training data,
在训练数据方面
高偏差模型因为太简单而欠拟合
the high bias model tends to not fit it
well since it's just too simple a model.
高方差模型趋向于完美拟合训练数据
The high variance model tends to
fit the training data really well
因为它完全匹配了每个点
since it's designed for it.
Finally, the good model tends
to fit the training data well.
最终 最佳模型对训练数据的拟合刚刚好
Now, when it comes to the testing data,
然后 在测试数据方面
the high bias model
tends to perform poorly.
高偏差模型的效果会很差
高方差模型也是
And so does the high variance model.
The good model is the one that
performs well in the testing data.
而最佳模型在测试数据上的效果较好